Richard York Gallery
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Richard York Gallery records
circa 1865-2005, bulk 1981-2004
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Richard York Gallery
79.3 linear feet
The records of the Richard York Gallery, a New York gallery specializing in American art from early 1800s to 1950, measure 79.3 linear feet and date from circa 1865-2005, with the bulk of the material dating from 1981 to 2004. Three-fourths of the records are artists' artwork files, documenting the sale and consignment of nearly 6,500 works of art. The gallery's activities are also recorded through correspondence, client files, gallery invoices, inventories, business and financial records, printed materials, scrapbooks, photographic materials of artwork, and estate records for the John Marin estate and Sergio Stella estate (Joseph Stella).
Provenance
The Richard York Gallery records were donated to the Archives of American Art in 2006 by Kevin Scott, the executor of Richard York's estate.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Accruals
Additional material is expected for this collection.
Historical Note
Richard T. York (circa 1950-2003) opened his eponymous gallery in the spring of 1981 on East 65th Street in New York City. Specializing in American painting and sculpture from early 1800s to 1950, the Richard York Gallery dealt in the artwork of hundreds of artists including Albert Bierstadt, Charles Demuth, Arthur Dove, Lockwood de Forest, John Graham, Georgia O'Keeffe, John Singer Sargent, Charles Sheeler, and Steve Wheeler. It also represented the estates of artists John Marin and Joseph Stella.
Richard York passed away in April 2003, and the gallery closed in May 2004.
Scope and Content Note
The records of the Richard York Gallery, a New York gallery specializing in American art from early 1800s to 1950, measure 79.3 linear feet and date from circa 1865-2005, with the bulk of the material dating from 1981 to 2004. Three-fourths of the records are artists' artwork files, documenting the sale and consignment of nearly 6,500 works of art. The gallery's activities are also recorded through correspondence, client files, gallery invoices, inventories, business and financial records, printed materials, scrapbooks, photographic materials of artwork, and estate records for the John Marin estate and Sergio Stella estate (Joseph Stella).
Correspondence includes both incoming and outgoing correspondence with collectors, clients, galleries and museums, primarily regarding appraisals, consignments, exhibitions, general inquiries, loans, and sales. Also found are scattered transactional records, information sheets for artwork, and photographic materials. Correspondence from the mid-late 1980s is poorly represented.
The sale and consignment of nearly 6,500 pieces of artwork at the Richard York Gallery are documented through transactional records, photographic materials, correspondence, and scattered printed materials found in the Artists' Artwork Files. Artists for which there are significant quantities of materials (over 50 folders) include Joseph Goldyne, Ellen Day Hale, John Henry Hill, John William Hill, Lester George Hornby, Louis Lozowick, Luigi Lucioni, Emma Fordyce MacRae, John Marin, Joseph Stella, William Henry Stevens, and Steve Wheeler. Also included are the files of the Richard York photography collection, which contained works by Robert Mapplethorpe.
Similar to the Artists' Artwork Files, Client Files document the sale and consignment of artwork, but are arranged by artist's and client's name. Materials found are primarily from the early 1990s and include correspondence, notes, photographic materials, photocopied client information cards, and printed materials.
The Richard York Gallery represented the John Marin estate and the Sergio Stella estate (Joseph Stella). The records of the John Marin estate are primarily artwork in-take sheets from 1998 and inventory lists from 2001. The Sergio Stella Estate records include correspondence, inventories of artwork by Joseph Stella, and some photographic materials.
Sales and inventory records contain a nearly complete set of gallery invoices from 1995-2000, and 2004. Inventories includes gallery inventory lists, and inventory cards of sold artwork from 1981-1997 (bulk 1981-1991).
The business and financial records include accounting records, bank deposit records, corporate records, index cards for contacts, invoices for gallery expenses, materials related to Richard York's involvement in the ADAA, mailing lists, records of payments to consignors, receipts, shipping records, and tax records. The gallery migrated from paper records to Artbase, an artwork management system, around 2000-2002. Included are two CDs of database data and digital images from Artbase, as well as inventories of the digital file names.
Printed materials contain advertising tear sheets from 1998-2002, exhibition catalogs, magazine and newspaper clippings of reviews and announcements, and other miscellaneous printed materials. Printed materials are also found in eight scrapbooks which document the activities of the Richard York Gallery, Richard York, and the gallery's exhibitions from 1981-2002. Materials in the scrapbooks include clippings, correspondence, photographs, exhibition catalogs, announcements, and invitations.
Photographic materials includes color photographs, transparencies, digital prints, and scattered printed materials, as well as over 600 slides of artwork, primarily works of art which were sold or consigned by the gallery. Artists for which there is significant volume of transparencies include Houghton Cranford Smith and Lockwood de Forest, Sr.
Materials with dates prior to 1981 in this collection are primarily research materials for works of art, such as printed materials, correspondence, and transparencies, as well as some artwork artifacts, such as back labels.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 9 series:
Series 1: Correspondence, 1975-2005 (Boxes 1-7; 6.4 linear feet)
Series 2: Artists' Artwork Files, circa 1865-2004 (Boxes 7-64; 56.85 linear feet)
Series 3: Client Files, 1965, circa 1981-circa 2004 (Box 64; 0.5 linear feet)
Series 4: Estate Records, 1983-circa 2004 (Boxes 64-65; 1.0 linear feet)
Series 5: Sales and Inventory Records, 1977-2004 (Boxes 65-70; 5.0 linear feet)
Series 6: Business and Financial Records, 1974-2005 (Boxes 70-77; 6.25 linear feet)
Series 7: Printed Materials, 1980-2004 (Boxes 77-78; 1.1 linear feet)
Series 8: Scrapbooks, 1981-2002 (Boxes 78, 80; 1.0 linear feet)
Series 9: Photographic Materials, 1977-2004 (Boxes 78-79; 1.2 linear feet)
Names and Subject Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects:
De Forest, Lockwood, 1850-1932; Goldyne, Joseph R.; Hale, Ellen Day, 1855-1940; Hill, John Henry, 1839-1922; Hill, J. W. (John William), 1812-1879; Hornby, Lester George, 1882-1956; Lozowick, Louis, 1892-1973; Lucioni, Luigi, 1900-1988; MacRae, Elmer Livingston, 1875-1953; Marin, John, 1870-1953; Marin, John, Jr. 1915?-1988; Smith, Houghton Cranford, 1887-1983; Stella, Joseph, 1877-1946; Stevens, Will Henry, 1881-1949; Wheeler, Steve, 1912-1992; Art Dealers Association of America
Subjects-Topical:
Art galleries, Commercial New York (State) New York; Art, American
Types of Materials:
CD-ROMs; Digital images; Photographs; Slides (photographs); Scrapbooks; Transparencies
Names:
Mapplethorpe, Robert
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Correspondence, 1975-2005, Series 1:; (Boxes 1-7; 6.4 linear feet)
  Correspondence spans the life of the gallery and contains incoming and outgoing correspondence with collectors, potential clients, galleries and museums regarding appraisals, consignments, donations, exhibitions, general inquiries, loans, and sales.
  The series is arranged as 2 subseries:
  1.1: Alphabetical, 1975-2005
  1.2: Subject, 1979-2004
  - Alphabetical, 1975-2005, 1.1:
    Alphabetical correspondence includes incoming and outgoing correspondence with collectors, potential clients, galleries, and museums regarding inquiries, consignments, and sales. The files of Executive Vice President Susan Menconi (1993-1998) and Gallery Manager Michael Mikulay (1996-1997) are included, as well as scattered gallery receipts and invoices, information sheets for artwork, and photographic materials. Correspondence from 1985-1990 is poorly represented.
    The bulk of the alphabetical correspondence was originally grouped by year(s) and filed alphabetically. The original order has been maintained, with general A-Z correspondence filed first in chronological order, followed by folders filed alphabetically by correspondent's last name or organization name.
    - A-Z, 1981-1985, (23 folders) (Box 1, Folder 1-23)
    - A-Z [1999-2000 Correspondence Binders], 1997-2001, (Disassembled binders) (Box 1, Folder 24-31)
      A-H [Binder 1], 1999-2001 (8 folders)
    - A-Z [1999-2000 Correspondence Binders], 1997-2001, (Disassembled binders) (Box 2, Folder 1-17)
      I-N [Binder 2], 1998-2001 (7 folders)
      O-Z [Binder 3], 1997-2000 (10 folders)
    - A-Z [2001 Correspondence Binders], 1993-2003, (Disassembled binders) (Box 2, Folder 18-41)
      H-R [Binder 2], 1993-2003 (10 folders)
      S-Z [Binder 3], 1999-2001 (6 folders)
    - A-Z [2002 Correspondence], 1998-2003, (6 folders) (Box 2, Folder 42-47)
    - A-Z [2002 Correspondence], 1998-2003, (23 folders) (Box 3, Folder 1-23)
    - A-Z [2003-2004 Correspondence], 1998-2004, (14 folders) (Box 3, Folder 24-37)
    - A-Z [Correspondence Unfiled], 1998-2003 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - A-Z, Susan Menconi's Files, 1984-2000, (13 folders) (Box 3, Folder 39-51)
    - A-Z, Susan Menconi's Files, 1984-2000, (19 folders) (Box 4, Folder 1-19)
    - A-Z, Michael Mikulay's Files, 1984-2000, (8 folders) (Box 5, Folder 1-8)
    - Andersen, Jan; Joan Burns Estate, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - The Art Newspaper, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - ArtNet.com, 1997-2002 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Bass, Robert M., 1990-2004 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Benetech, Inc., RYG 401(k) Plan and Trust, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Carey Ellis Co., Southwestern Bell Communications (SBC) Collection, 1996-1998 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Citibank, 1991-1999 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Fahlman, Betsy; Graham Gallery (New York), 2002 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Fraenkel Gallery, Devil's Playground by Richard Misrach, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Friends of Art and Preservation in Embassies, 2000, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Gay Men's Health Crisis (GMHC) Benefit, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Goldyne, Joseph, 1991-1998, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 20-21)
    - Gundell, Peter and Vera, 1989-1999 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - The Huntington (San Marino, CA), 2004 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Jaffe, Irma, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Kronenberg, Gloria, 1975, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Laura C. Smith Art Trust, Nancy Tonachio (Houghton Cranford Smith), 1995-2001 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Lesbian and Gay Community Services Center, Mirror Donation, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Lettera, Josephine, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Lobell, Katherine, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Lotos Club, 1998-2002 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Lowecamp, Norma, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Lucioni, Luigi, circa 1981-2004 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Manoogian, Richard, Epic Fine Arts, 1991-1997 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - MKG Art Management (Houston, TX), 2003-2004 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Morris, Neil, 2000-2002 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Morrissey, Francis X., Esq., 2001 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Ross, Wilbur and Judith, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Rowe Fine Art [Bisttram Photos], 2001 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - San Francisco Museum of Modern Art (SFMOMA), 2000-2001 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Sotheby's, 1993-1997 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - The Speed Art Museum, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Spiro, Harry, 1991-1997 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Stella, Armand, 1993-1997 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Trisorio, Lucia; Studio Trisorio, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Umbach, Mark; James H. Ricau Estate, 1993-1997 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - USArtists American Fine Art Show, 2005, (Includes computer zip disc) (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts (Richmond, VA), 2004 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Weimer, Walter, 1994-1996 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Steve Wheeler Estate, 1997-1999 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Williford, Graham, 1990-2000 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - York, Richard; Personal, 1996-2000 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - York, Richard; Personal, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Subject, 1979-2004, 1.2:
    Originally filed by subject by the gallery, materials in this subseries concern appraisals, consignments, donations, loans, and a handful of exhibitions or pieces of artwork. Also found is some correspondence regarding Richard T. York's personal collection. The bulk of the subject correspondence is from the 1990s-2004.
    - Appraisals, A-W, 1980-1997, (20 folders, Disassembled binder) (Box 6, Folder 5-24)
    - Appraisals, A-S, 1998-2004 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Appraisals, Winslow Homer, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Appraisals, The Shelbourne Museum, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - "California" Exhibition (1996-1997) [Susan Menconi File], 1996 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Consignment Letters, Unsigned, 1998-2002 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Consignment Memoranda, Consigned To, 1997-2004 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Consignment Memoranda, Signed, 1998-2001 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Consignment Memoranda, Unsigned, 1998-2000 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Consignments, Active: A-C, 1994-2004 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Consignments, Active: C-G, 1996-2004 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Consignments, Active: H, 1995-2003 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Consignments, Active: H-M, 1993-2004 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Consignments, Active: N-R, 1994-2004 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Consignments, Active: R-T, 1992-2004 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Consignments, Active: T-Z, 1990-2004 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Consignments, Consigned From, 1996-2004 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Consignments, Notification of Sale: A-D, 1991-1998 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Consignments, Notification of Sale: E-L, 1991-2000 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Consignments, Notification of Sale: M-P, 1992-1998 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Consignments, Notification of Sale: R-Z, 1991-2000 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Donations, 2000-2001 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Donations, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Donations, DirectEffect Fire Island Pines Auction, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - "Drawings and Watercolors by John William Hill" Exhibition (April 11 - May 20, 2003), 2003 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Eakins, Thomas, Cowboys in the Badlands, 2001-2002 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Loans, Artwork on Loan, 1996-1997, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Loans, Artwork To Go On Loan, 1997, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Loans, Requests and Forwarded, 1996-1997 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Resumes, 1998-2002 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Richard T. York Personal Collection, 1979-1984, 1991-1998 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Richard T. York Photograph Collection, circa 1990s-2000s (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Sales and Consignments, Pending and Purchases, 1994-1995 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Seymour Lawrence Estate, Study, New York by John Marin [Susan Menconi File], 1993- 1995 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Artists' Artwork Files, circa 1865-2004, Series 2:; (Boxes 7-64; 56.85 linear feet)
  Artists' Artwork Files contain materials related to the sale and consignment of works of art. Each work of art was assigned an inventory number when it was taken in by the gallery, made up of a unique three- or four-digit number followed by a two-letter code (i.e. 2549CY). The numbers were assigned in numerical order, therefore smaller numbers indicate an earlier intake date and larger numbers, a more recent intake date. The two-letter code indicates the type of transaction: consignment ("CY"), loan ("LY"), joint venture ("JY"), or the Richard York Gallery inventory ("RY"). Researchers should note that artwork may have multiple inventory numbers or may be described by alternate titles as a result of being taken in by the gallery on more than one occasion.
  2.1: General, circa 1865-2004
  2.2: Photography Collection, 2003-2004
  - General, circa 1865-2004, 2.1:
    Originally known as the "paintings files" by the Richard York Gallery, this subseries provides comprehensive documentation for the gallery's artwork. Found are sales, consignment, and loan records; correspondence related to transactions; research materials; and photographs, slides, and transparencies. Folders include many photocopies of original documents. Artists for which there are significant quantities of materials (over 50 folders) include Joseph Goldyne, Ellen Day Hale, John Henry Hill, John William Hill, Lester George Hornby, Louis Lozowick, Luigi Lucioni, Emma Fordyce MacRae, John Marin, Joseph Stella, William Henry Stevens, and Steve Wheeler.
    The bulk of the materials in this subseries are dated from 1981 to 2004, and includes active files from the gallery's closing in April 2004, documenting the disposition of artwork. Materials dated prior to 1981 are typically artwork artifacts such as back labels, or research materials. Researchers should also consult Client Files regarding particular artists. Additional related records may also be found in the Artbase CDs found in Business and Financial Records.
    Folder titles are described and arranged according to the gallery's filing system: first by artists' last name, then numerically by the inventory number. A placeholder found in this series has been left in its original location upon accession; however, it is unknown if the location of the placeholder remained relevant to the filing order of the records.
    - Adams, Ansel, 2678CY: Clearing Winter Storm, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Adams, Ansel, 4951CY: Clearing Winter Storm, Yosemite National Park, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Alberry, Agnes, 2660RY: Still Life: Roses, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Albers, Josef, 8995CY: Untitled Abstraction, 2002-2004 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3723CY: Mission Priest, 1992-1994 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3724CY: Mission San Luis Rey, San Juan Capistrano, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3725CY: Mission Dolores, 1992-1994 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3726CY: San Luis Rey de Francia, California, 1992-1994 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3727CY: Cross at Mission San Luis Rey, San Juan Capistrano, 1992- 1993 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3728CY: Old Mission, San Diego, California, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3729CY: Panama-Pacific International Exposition at Night, 1992- 1993 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3730CY: Panama-Pacific Exposition, Portals, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3731CY: Panama-Pacific International Exposition Fountain, 1992- 1993 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3732CY: Stackpole Figures, Panama-Pacific International Exposition, 1992- 1993 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3733CY: San Francisco Street, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3734CY: Reflecting Pool and Temple, Panama-Pacific International Exposition, 1992- 1993 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3735CY: Shoveling Out Truckee, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3736CY: Horses Grazing, Tamalpais, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3737CY: Golden Gate, San Francisco, California, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3738CY: Landscape, California, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3739CY: Lake Tahoe, California, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3740CY: Landscape, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3741CY: Landscape in the Sierras, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3742CY: California, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3743CY: Ghost Tree, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3744CY: Portrait of a Woman, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3745CY: Portrait of a Girl, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3746CY: Girl Seated, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3747CY: Charm, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3748CY: Portrait, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3749CY: Woman in White, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3750CY: Funeral Procession, Chinatown, San Francisco, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3751CY: Funeral, Chinatown, San Francisco, 1992-1994 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3752CY: Street Corner, Chinatown, San Francisco, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3753CY: Man Smoking a Pipe, Chinatown, San Francisco, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3754CY: Chinatown, San Francisco, 1992-1994 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3755CY: Vegetable Market, Chinatown, San Francisco, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3756CY: Street Scene, Chinatown, San Francisco, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3757CY: Man and Child, Chinatown, San Francisco, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3758CY: In a Market, Chinatown, San Francisco, 1992-1994 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3759CY: A Street in Chinatown, San Francisco, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3760CY: Young Citizen and Grandfather, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3761CY: Mourners at Funeral, 1992-1994 (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3762CY: Funeral Gathering, Chinatown, San Francisco, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3954CY: San Francisco Burning, Earthquake 1906, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3963CY: Beach Scene, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3964CY: Chinese Girl in White, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 3965CY: Street Scene, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 4741RY: Panama-Pacific Exposition, Portals, circa 1996 (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 4742RY: Panama-Pacific Exposition, Fountain, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 4743RY: Vegetable Market, Chinatown, San Francisco, 1996-1999 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - Albrecht, Herman O., 9467RY: Sailing Ships, Alcatraz, San Francisco, circa 2003-2004 (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - Albright, Gertrude Partington, 4924CY: Fusai, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 66)
    - Alexander, Francesca, 1289CY: Charity, 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - Alexander, Francesca, 2802CY: Charity, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - Alexander, Francesca, 2803LY: Text with Asphodel and Grass, 1983, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - Alexander, Francesca, 2804LY: Text with Wild Tulips, Wild Oats, Trefort, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - Alexander, Francesca, 3800CY: Text with Asphodel and Grass, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 71)
    - Alexander, Henry, 4470CY: A Portrait, 1995-1997 (Box 7, Folder 72)
    - Alexander, Henry, 6112CY: The Letter Home, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 73)
    - Alexander, John White, 1623CY: The Bronze Bowl, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 74)
    - Alexander, John White, 1831CY: Cornish Landscape, 1986-1987, 1996-1997 (Box 7, Folder 75)
    - Allen, Thomas, 7583CY: Laurel, 2000-2003 (Box 7, Folder 76)
    - Alvarez-Bravo, Manuel, 3105RY: Three Photographic Prints, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 77)
    - American Aesthetic Movement, 3709RYabcde: Parlor Suite Sette, Four Chairs, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 78)
    - American Aesthetic Movement, 3943RY: Two Ebonized Side Chairs, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 79)